[{"Notes": "She competed in the blind swimming events in seven Paralympic Games, from 1980 to 2004, and won 55 medals \u2013 41 of which were gold", "Question": "Who is the most decorated Paralympian in the history of the Games?", "Options": ["Trischa Zorn of USA", "Mike Kenny of Great Britain", "Jonas Jacobsson of Sweden", "Erin Popovich of USA"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Notes": "Natalia Partyka, the Polish table tennis player, also competed in the Olympics and Paralympics in 2008.", "Question": "In 2008 distance swimmer Natalie Du Toit became the first athlete to carry her country\u2019s flag at the opening ceremonies of both the Olympics and Paralympics. Which country did she represent?", "Options": ["Australia", "USA", "New Zealand", "South Africa"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Notes": "The motto was \"Mind, Body, Spirit\" until 2004.", "Question": "What is the motto of the Paralympic Games?", "Options": ["\"Never Broken by Hardship or Battle\"", "\"World in Motion\"", "\"To Conquer is to Live\"", "\"Spirit in Motion\""], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Which of these sports will not feature in Rio?", "Options": ["Five-a-side football", "Seven-a-side football", "11-a-side football", "None of above"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Notes": "The first winter Paralympic Games took place in \u00d6rnsk\u00f6ldsvik in 1976.", "Question": "In which city did the first official Paralympic Games take place (in 1960)?", "Options": ["Tokyo", "New York", "Melbourne", "Rome"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Notes": "Vinicius, the Olympics mascot, is named after the other co-author: Vinicius des Moraes.", "Question": "Who is the Paralympic mascot, Tom, named after?", "Options": ["Thomas Guttmann, who organised the 1948 Stoke Mandeville Games, a precursor to the Paralympic Games", "Tom Jobim, the co-author of the Brazilian song The Girl from Ipanema", "Tom Brady, husband of Brazilian super model Gisele B\u00fcndchen", "Tom\u00e9 Silva, Brazil's most decorated Paralympian"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "She went on to became the youngest recipient of an MBE at the age of 14.", "Question": "How old was Ellie Simmonds when she won two gold medals for Great Britain in Beijing in 2008?", "Options": [9.0, 11.0, 13.0, 15.0], "Answers": "C"}, {"Notes": "Szekeres won a bronze medal in the fencing competition at the 1988 Olympics Seoul. After being injured in a bus accident in 1991 he took up wheelchair fencing and went on to win medals at five different Paralympic Games.", "Question": "In 1992, P\u00e1l Szekeres became the first athlete to win medals at both the Olympics and Paralympics. In which sport did the Hungarian compete?", "Options": ["Archery", "Fencing", "100m butterfly", "Powerlifting"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "There will be more participants than ever, with Aruba, Congo, Malawi, Somalia, Sao Tome and Principe, and Togo taking part for the first time.", "Question": "How many athletes are competing in the Paralympics in Rio?", "Options": [889.0, 1555.0, 2016.0, 4350.0], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Which country topped the medal table in 2012 with 231 medals, including 95 golds?", "Options": ["Great Britain", "USA", "Russia", "China"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Who of the following lit the cauldron at the 2016 Summer Paralympic Games?", "Options": ["Andre Brasil", "Clodoaldo Silvax", "Daniel Dias", "Terezinha Guilhermina"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Who will host the Winter Paralympics in 2018?", "Options": ["Brazil", "Austria", "Norway", "South Korea"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Notes": "The First Paralympic Games were held in Rome, Italy from September 18 to 25, 1960, with the 1960 Summer Olympics.", "Question": "When were the first paralympic games?", "Options": [1940.0, 1960.0, 1976.0, 1990.0], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "True. Since 2012, athletes who had visual impairment (ranging from partial vision to total blindness) could win medals at the Paralympics. The sighted guides for athletes with visual impairment have such an essential role that they can win a medal with the visual impaired individual as the from a team.", "Question": "Athlete with visual impairment may participate in the Paralympics.", "Options": ["True", "False"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Notes": "United Stated has won 2352 medals in Paralympic Games.", "Question": "Which country has won the most Paralympic medals?", "Options": ["USA", "Germany", "China", "Canada"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Notes": "China had 308 athletes.", "Question": "Which country had the largest Paralympics team of 2016 Rio Paralympics?", "Options": ["USA", "Germany", "China", "Canada"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Who will host the Summer Paralympics in 2020?", "Options": ["South Korea", "Japan", "Austria", "Norway"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "The term Paralympic Games came into official use at the 1988 Games in Seoul. Prior to this, such terms as International Games for the Physically Disabled and the Olympiad for the Disabled were used. The Games are sanctioned by the International Olympic Committee (IOC) as are the Special Olympics World Games (for athletes with intellectual disabilities) and the Deaflympics.", "Question": "\u00a0According to the IPC (International Paralympic Committee) what is the official reason that this global multi-sports event is called the Paralympic Games?", "Options": ["They are attended by a large number of paramedics.", "They were originally for athletes suffering from paraplegia.", "They run alongside or parallel to the Olympic Games.", "The athletes are paragons of their sports."], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "The seed of the Paralympic Games was a 1948 sporting competition held at Stoke Mandeville hospital, near Aylesbury, in England. This event for veterans of the Second World War suffering from spinal injuries was largely organised by a man born in which country?", "Options": ["France", "Germany", "USA", "Greece"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "Since there were no more than three athletes or teams per event, every athlete was guaranteed to win a medal. The home team Italy were top of the medals table, followed by Great Britain and West Germany.", "Question": "In 1960, the 9th Annual International Stoke Mandeville Games were held in Rome in tandem with the Summer Olympics there. With 400 athletes from 23 countries taking part, these are officially regarded as the first Paralympic Games. What was unusual about these games?", "Options": ["The blind sprinters ran with guide dogs.", "At least half of the competitors were able bodied.", "Every athlete won a medal.", "They included wheelchair gymnastics."], "Answers": "C"}, {"Notes": "After Rome in 1960 and Tokyo in 1964, Mexico refused to host the Paralympics in 1968 so they went to Tel Aviv in Israel. The games were held in the same country as the Munich and Montreal Olympics in 1972 and 1976 respectively, but not the same city (Heidelberg and Toronto). Moscow's attitudes were highlighted by an official at the Moscow Olympics who, when asked by a Western journalist if they would participate at the games in Arnhem, the Netherlands, reputedly replied \"There are no invalids in the USSR\". The LA games of 1984 were accompanied by the Paras of Stoke Mandeville and New York. From Seoul 1988 onwards, the two games have been in the same city. ", "Question": "From 1964 to 1984, what was the only city to play host to the Olympics and Paralympic Games in the same year?", "Options": ["Mexico City", "Los Angeles", "Montreal", "\u00a0Tokyo"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Notes": "Boccia is for athletes with cerebral palsy and other severe disabilities involving motor skills. It is a bowling game with blue or red balls aimed at a white jack. Athletes who are too severely disabled to propel the balls with their hands and feet use ramps.\u00a0", "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a Paralympic sport primarily for the visually impaired?", "Options": ["Goalball", "Boccia", "Football 5-a-side", "Judo"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "The three agitos (from the Latin for \"I move\") of red, blue and green, encircling a common centre represent athletes coming from all over the globe and also the Olympic motto \"spirit in motion\". This symbol has been used at the games since 2003. Other Paralympic symbols are the mascots such as Lizzie, the Sydney lizard, Fu Niu Lele, the multi-coloured cow in Beijing and Mandeville, the London mascot named in honour of the English hospital that hosted the precursor to the games.", "Question": "The Paralympic flag consists of three asymmetric crescents called agitos. Which two colours are found on the Olympic flag but NOT on the Paralympic flag?", "Options": ["Blue and yellow", "Yellow and black", "Black and blue", "Green and black"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "In which Paralympic swimming category are you most likely to see assistants called tappers?", "Options": ["S1", "S9", "S11", "S14"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Are there Winter Paralympic Games?", "Options": [1], "Answers": "A"}, {"Notes": "As it happens, the gold for the 2004 wheelchair rugby went neither to Canada, who invented the game, nor to the USA, but to New Zealand. The documentary is an example of the increased profile of the Games over the years. With many countries already showing hours of live Paralympic coverage, the IPC made the sport available to even more people in 2012 by webcasting over 750 hours of coverage on its Youtube channel.", "Question": "Wheelchair or quad rugby is a sport notorious for its violent wheelchair collisions. In 2005 it was the subject of an Oscar nominated documentary called \"Murderball\", after the original name for the sport. The film centred around the run up to the 2004 Paralympics and the rivalry between the USA and which other country?", "Options": ["China", "Canada", "Mexico", "Great Britain"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Notes": "She competed in the blind swimming events in seven Paralympic Games, from 1980 to 2004, and won 55 medals \u2013 41 of which were gold", "Question": "Trischa Zorn, a Paralympic swimmer, holds the record for the most gold medals ever won in international competition. How many gold medals has she won?", "Options": [7.0, 17.0, 26.0, 41.0], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Who came up with the idea for the Paralympics?", "Options": ["Ludwig Guttmann", "Tanni Grey-Thompson", "Esther Vergeer", "Daniel Dias"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "There is an age limit for Paralympic Games participants. True or False?", "Options": ["True", "False"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "The Paralympic Games are the second largest sports competition after the Olympic Games. True or False?", "Options": ["True", "False"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "Several athletes with disabilities have competed in both the Olympic Games and Paralympic Games. In London 2012, Pistorius became the first amputee to run at the Summer Olympic Games, where he competed in the 400m and 4 \u00d7 400 relay events, but did not win a medal", "Question": "Paralympic athletes cannot participate in Olympic competitions. True or False?", "Options": ["True", "False"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "The Paralympics has the same Olympic rings as its symbol.", "Options": ["True", "False"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "The International Olympic Committee and International Paralympics Committee are the same entities.", "Options": ["True", "False"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "Goalball is played by visually impaired athletes and a special rule means there is no need for classification.Participants wear black-out masks to ensure everyone, whether blind or visually impaired, competes equally. The masks are checked during the game.", "Question": "\u00a0In which of these Paralympic Sports do players wear a mask?", "Options": ["Judo", "Goalball\u00a0", "Rowing", "Goalball\u00a0"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "\u00a0What sport does Sarah Storey compete in?", "Options": ["Swimming", "Cycling", "Both A and B", "None of the above"], "Answers": "C"}]